<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chetan Thapliyal · Cloud Engineer</title>
    <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chetan Thapliyal · Cloud Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technical Writer</title>
      <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/hashnode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/hashnode/</guid>
      <description>Transition to IT, started freelance blogging and Technical Writing ✍🏼 As a lifelong tech enthusiast, I made an exciting career shift into the dynamic world of IT in December 2022, focusing on the exciting fields of Cloud Engineering and DevOps. My ingrained &amp;lsquo;geek&amp;rsquo; tendencies fueled a passion for Linux and Git version control, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for five years in both personal and professional projects. This foundation gave me a head start with DevOps concepts and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging</title>
      <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/reportindia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/reportindia/</guid>
      <description>Transition to IT, started freelance blogging and Technical Writing ✍🏼 Developed a news blogging website focused on Finance and Tech. Authored regular news articles and built an online following. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subject Matter Expert - Chegg India</title>
      <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/chegg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/chegg/</guid>
      <description>Life as a Subject Matter Expert Chegg India is a leading student-first connected learning platform, Chegg&amp;rsquo;s Student Hub makes higher education more affordable and more accessible, all while improving student outcomes. Chegg is a publicly-held company based in Santa Clara, CA with offices in San Francisco, New York, Portland, India, Israel, Berlin, and Ukraine.
During my work at Chegg I provided authoritative and accurate solutions to complex technical challenges, ensuring client satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Field Engineer (Mechanical) - Emakina.NL</title>
      <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/jaypee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/jaypee/</guid>
      <description>Life in field Jaiprakash Associates Limited, commonly known as Jaypee Group, is an Indian conglomerate company headquartered in Noida, Uttar Pradesh, with interests in engineering, construction, power, real estate, hospitality, IT, sports and education (non-profit).
In Jaiprakash Associates I was part of a Project Management team working on a Residential Building Project, with a cross-functional combination of roles from different providers, and the client, working together. The technical team was up to 7 people, but it was only a part of the whole - which included a dedicated QA engineering team, Mantainance engineering team, Senior Engineers, Project Managers, and a client representative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Manager</title>
      <link>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chetanthapliyal.github.io/experience/tbd/</guid>
      <description>First time joining the business as Manager Increased customer retention 15% through targeted digital marketing campaigns including email and social media Expanded business to 3 new geographic areas, leading to a 20% increase in overall annual revenue Implemented new technologies including Tally accounting software, UPI payment processing to modernize traditional business operations and improve efficiency. Secured 5 new major client accounts, contributing 30% to annual revenue Achieved 45% client retention rate through dedicated account management Led rebranding initiative, lowering marketing expenses by 20% Oversaw daily operations of book depot Handled daily sales and customer service </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
